In the last lecture, we made sure that we show a spinner a loader to the user once the request is on
Son dersimizde, bir eiticiye, talebin yolda olduunu kullancya bir ykleyici gsterdiinden
its way.
emin olduk.
That's of course a good thing to do, it improves our user experience because user clearly sees that something
Elbette bunun yaplmas iyi bir ey, kullanc deneyimini gelitirdiinden, kullanc bir eyler olduunu
is happening,
aka grr.
it's also an improvement to the user experience if we show error messages in case something fails.
Bir eylerin baarsz olmas durumunda hata iletileri gsteriyorsak, kullanc deneyiminin de bir gelimesidir.
And here again there are different places where you could show such an error message,
Ve burada yine byle bir hata mesaj gsterebileceiniz farkl yerler var.
I simply want to set up some global error handler which shows a modal with the error message but doesn't
Yalnzca modsal bir Swiftie hata mesaj gsteren baz genel hata ileyici ayarlamak istiyorum,
use the modal here because I don't want to be stuck to this container, to the burger builder container.
ancak buradaki modal' kullanmyor nk buradaki konteynerde Bergere Boulder konteynerine skmak istemiyorum.
I want to have a flexible way of showing an error no matter which component and which container
Hangi bileen ve hangi konteyner olutuuna baklmakszn esnek bir ekilde hata
it occurs.
gstermek istemiyorum.
So therefore my modal is going to get added to a higher level in the application and I want to have
Dolaysyla bu nedenle modalim uygulamada daha st seviyeye eklenecek ve uygulamadan daha yksek bir
a higher level of the application, so some higher component then this burger builder container where I catch
seviyeye sahip olmak istiyorum. Dolaysyla, hatalar yakalamak iin nerede daha yksek bir bileen ve Asperger
errors and where I then make sure that my error modal is displayed.
Bodor konteyneri koyaym ve burada hata veya modalimin grntlenir.
Now where can we set this up?
imdi bunu nereden ayarlayabiliriz.
How can we control this?
Bunu nasl kontrol edebiliriz.
I simply want to create a higher order component with which I can wrap the burger builder or which I'll
bileeni sarabilir veya modal olarak kullanabilir ve hata ileme ilevselliini uygun bir ekilde ona ekleyebilir.
actually use in that second way I showed you for using higher order components, so that we can simply
Yalnzca buger yapcy sarabilmem iin veya daha nce yksek emir bileenleri kullanmak iin
wrap any component which should have this error modal with it and can conveniently add the error
gsterdiim ikinci bir ekilde kullanacam daha yksek bir sipari bileeni oluturmak istiyorum, bylece
handling functionality to it.
bu hataya sahip herhangi bir
So for this, I'm going to create a new higher order component in a folder which I'll name withError
Bunun iin bunun iin, hata ileyicisi ile isimlendireceim bir klasrde yeni bir yksek sipari
Handler.
bileeni oluturacam.
I'm using this syntax withErrorHandler because I want to use this second way of creating a high order
Bu szdizimini hata ileyicisi ile kullanyorum nk kullanmak istiyorum, burada X tahtasnda kullanlacak ve
component which will be used here on the export and not used as
kullanlmayan yksek dereceli bir bileen oluturmak iin ikinci yol.
jsx code.
X kodu.
So if they are all added with errorHandler.js file and this file here now will take the following
Bylece hepsi hava tahmini vericisi J ile eklendi ve bu dosya buradan u andaki
form,
halini ald.
it will be a function with error handler
Hata ileyicisi ile bir ilev olacaktr.
and this should be a function which takes the wrapped component as an input and which then returns a
Ve bu, sarlm bileeni bir girdi olarak alan ve daha sonra sahne alan bir
function which receives props
ilevi dndren bir ilev olmaldr.
and of course simply returns these, some jsx including the wrapped component.
Ve elbette sadece Steese'i geri gnderirim Ben sarlm bileen dahil Chia'nn X'iyim.
So for that we need to import React from react
Dolaysyla yeniden davranmak iin tekrar hareket etmemiz gerekiyor.
and now here I of course want to return the wrapped component and distribute any props this component
herhangi bir Propst'i datmak istiyorum, nk bu sahneyi tanmyorum ama kesinlikle onlar kaybetmek istemiyorum.
might receive on it because I don't know these props but I definitely don't want to lose them.
Ve imdi burada elimde sarl bileeni geri getirmek ve bu aletin alabilecei
I then want to export this withErrorHandler function as the default
Sonra hata ileyici ilevini varsaylan olarak da aktarmak istiyorum.
but now I also want to use my or add my error modal.
Ama imdi imdi de kullanmak istiyorum ya da hata veya modalm ekliyorum.
So for that I need to import two things,
Bunun iin iki ey ithal etmeliyim.
the modal component of course from the components UI modal folder and there is modal.js file
Elbette ki modal bileen bileenleri sizin veya ben modal klasr ve orada D-Mo. js dosyas.
and since I want to place it next to it I need to Aux component from the aux folder in the HOC folder.
Ve onu yanna yerletirmek istediimden, HLC klasrndeki ox klasrnden alks bileenine ihtiyacm var.
So now I can wrap that all with aux like this and add the modal next to it,
imdi hepsini bu gibi alks ile ve yanndaki modalde sarmalayabilirim.
don't use a self-closing tag here because in the modal of course I want to output something.
Kendiliinden kapanan bir etiket kullanmayn, nk elbette modal olarak bir ey kartmak istiyorum.
For now I'll just say something didn't work, just like that
imdilik bir eylerin byle ie yaramadn syleyeceim.
Now we can finetune this but this is what I want to show right now,
imdi sizi bu dnyada bulamyoruz ama u an gstermek istediim ey bu.
now let's see if this works. If we save this, we now have our higher order component,
imdi bunu yapalm, eer bunu kaydedersek, yksek mertebeden bir bileene sahip olduumuzu grelim.
let's now use this on the burger builder.
imdi bunu Bergere Boulder'da kullanalm.
There I will
Yapacam.
import it at the top so withErrorHandler starting with a lowercase character because we're not going to
ileci ile, j'yi X olarak kullanmayacam ve imdi tm HNC klasrne
use it in jsx and now I'll navigate to my HOC folder and there to the withErrorHandler folder and the withErrorHandler.js
gidelim ve 2D ile birlikte hava ileme ileci klasr Anthi ile birlikte H hata ileyicisi J'ye sahip.
file of course, and then take that withErrorHandler function we're importing and
dersi alp hata ileyici ileviyle almak ve burger Boulder' buna benzer ekilde sarmak.
wrap the burger builder with it like this.
Veya en stte, kk harf karakteriyle balayan hata
Now with this if we go back to the withErrorHandler function, set show like this so to true simply
Hava ileme fonksiyonu ile geri dnersek, imdi bunu modle geirdiimizde geree dntrecek ve
on the modal, if we save this and go back we should always see something didn't work.
geriye dnersek her zaman bir eyin ie yaramadn greceiz.
Now obviously we only want to show this if we got an error
Akas, yalnzca bir hata yaparsak bunu gstermek istiyoruz.
so we need to set show to something else and that something else needs to come from the wrapped component
Dolaysyla ovu baka bir ey haline getirmeliyiz ve sarf edilen bileenden baka bir
we need that information.
eyin gelmesi gerekiyor.
If it did fail to get that information, we should add a second argument to our higher order function
Eer bu bilgiyi elde etmeyi baaramadysak, buradaki st dzey grevimize ikinci bir argman
here,
eklemeliyiz.
The axios instance which was used so that we can set up an error handler, a global error handler on it.
Kullanlan eski ABD rnei, bylece bir hata ileyicisi zerinde genel bir hata ileyicisi kurabiliriz.
Now to use that instance here, I will change this functional component into a class based one,
imdi burada staed rneini kullanmak iin bu ilevsel bileeni snf tabanl bir bileene getireceim.
so here I will return class which should now extend the component object from react so I need to import
Yani burada, bileen nesnesini tepki vermeden geniletecek olan snf geri vereceim, bylece anonim bir
that class extends component as you can see it's an anonymous class.
snf olduunu grebildiiniz gibi snf geniletme bileenini ieri aktarmak gerekiyor.
I don't set up a name here because I never use that class,
Ben burada isim yapmadm nk o snf hi kullanmadm.
I return it here,
Onu buraya geri gnderiyorum.
it's a class factory essentially, withErrorHandler creates these classes.
Aslnda bu snflar oluturan hata ileyicisi olan bir snf fabrikasdr.
Now in there, we clearly need a render method where we in the end return what we return in our functional
sonuta dndmze ve ilevsel bileenimize burada dneceimiz bir render yntemine kesinlikle ihtiyacmz var.
component here,
inde yok,
so simply return that. Of course props is now this.props since we changed it to a class,
Tabii geri dnn, tabii ki imdi bir pakete dntmz iin bu pervanenin paketi var.
we can get rid of that part
O paradan kurtulamayz.
down there now. And now with this, we can add componentDidMount here and in componentDidMount, we can
u andan itibaren u andan itibaren bileeni buraya ekleyebiliriz ve bileende bileen
now set up our axios listeners. So on the axios instance here we can now set up our global interceptor
eklemitik, imdi eriim rnekleminde eksenler dinleyicilerimizi ayarlayabiliriz, imdi burada hatalar ileyebilmemizi salayan
which also allows us to handle errors, so I'll add interceptors here
kresel engelleyiciyi kurabiliriz. Btn sektrleri buraya ekleyeceim.
then response and then with use at a function I want to use.
Sonra cevap verir ve sonra sizinle birlikte kullanmak istediim bir ilevdedir.
So this function here will get the response and then do something with it but I'm not really interested
bir eyler yapacak, ancak bu ilk argmana gerekten ilgi duymuyorum, bu yzden burada null geireceim.
in that first argument so I'll pass null here.
Bu ite burada bu ilev yant alacak ve onunla
The second argument is the one I'm interested in,
lgilendiim ikinci argman.
that's the error case where I get an error. Here
Burada bir hata mesaj geldiim hata durumu.
I then want to show my error modal,
Hatam veya modalemi gstermek istemiyorum.
So for that, I'll
ller iin.
now add a state where I will simply set error to null initially, and in here I will then set or call
imdi, balangta boluu yalnzca hata olarak ayarlayacam ve burada ayarlayacam bir durum ekledim, bu ayarlanm
this set state and set error
durum ve ayar hatas denildi.
to the error I'm getting here back from firebase and this happens to be an object which also contains
hatas ve mesaj mlknde bir hata mesaj da ieren bir nesne olmas mmkn.
an error message on the message property.
Q Burada firebase'den geri dnyorum
You can simply console log that error to see how this object looks like.
Bu nesnenin nasl grndn grmek iin yalnzca Konsole, bu hatay kilitleyebilir.
So now I'm setting that error here.
imdi bu hatay burada ayarlayacam.
Once we
Bir keresinde biz.
well got one. Now what I'll
Pekala Godwine imdi baka ne var.
also do is I'll add  a new interceptor for a request,
Tek yapmanz gereken bir istek iin yeni bir Interesse ayarlayc eklemektir.
so there, I'll call use and I'm not really interested in the request but there's one thing I want to do in there.
Bu yzden bizi aryorlar ve isteiyle gerekten ilgilenmiyorum, ancak orada yapmak istediim bir ey var.
I want to call this set state and clear any errors so that whenever I send the request I don't have
temizlemek istiyorum, bylece istei gnderirken burada hata yapmam iin artk kurmam gerekmiyor.
my error set up anymore so that I definitely clear it here.
Bu durumu "devlet" olarak adlandrmak ve hatalar
So now on the modal I will only show it if this state error is not null essentially
imdi cep telefonunda sadece bu durum hatas esas olarak bo deilse gstereceim.
and that in there I can output this state error and then again there will be a message property on the
Ve orada bu durum hatas ktlayabilir ve daha sonra tekrar yapmam gereken bir ey
error object returned by firebase. There is just one more thing we have to do,
daha vardr: Firebase tarafndan dndrlen hata nesnesinde bir mesaj zellii olacaktr.
the modal component we created also exposes the click property which occurs when we click the backdrop,
Oluturduumuz modal bileen de, zemini tkladmzda oluan tklama zelliini ortaya koyuyor.
and in this case, of course, I also want to clear the error because then we click the modal,
Ve elbette bu durumda da hatay temizlemek istiyoruz nk o zaman modal' tklyoruz.
I don't want to show it any more,
Artk gstermek istemiyorum.
I have to get rid of the error. So also add clicked here and there I will call a method
Hatadan kurtulmak zorundaym, bylece reklam burada tklad ve orada bir yntem aracam.
I have to create in my withErrorHandler component, I'll name it errorConfirmedHandler.
Benim hata ileyici bileeni ile oluturmak veya ad hata veya onaylanm ileyici var.
This simply is a method where I will call this set state and set error to null too
Bu, basite, bu ayar durumunu arp hatay iki bolua ayarlayabilen bir yntemdir.
and I will assign it here, this errorConfirmedHandler
Ve burada bu hata onayl ileyici atayacam.
Now with this set up here, there's one more thing I want to do,
imdi burada bu kadar ok ey yapmak istediim bir ey daha var.
this.state.error.message which I'm outputting here will throw an error initially because the modal component
Burada ktm durum hata mesaj balangta bir hata atacaktr, nk kalp bileeni
is always present even if we don't show it there.
her zaman var olsalar bile burada gsterilmez.
So what I'll do is I'll simply add a ternary expression where I'll say this.state.error ?
Dolaysyla ne yapacam, nihayetinde bu durum hata emniyet iareti yok denecek kadaryla
only if this is not null,
ifadelerini deitiriyor.
then I'll output that, otherwise I'll output null so I'll put nothing.
imdi o zaman aksi takdirde tm k null kt bu yzden hibir ey kt.
Now with that, if I save this and go back to the application, we'll get cannot read property interceptors
imdi bunu kaydedersem ve uygulamaya dnersek alamayacam, nk bunu altrmaya altk,
which makes sense because we try to run this on
mantkl olan zellik arabirimleri okunamyor.
axios but we don't receive axios, we expect to get it as an argument.
X evet, ancak X almadmz bir argman olarak almay umuyoruz.
But in the burger builder where I use withErrorHandler, I'm only passing the burger builder component,
Ancak hata ileyicisi ile birlikte kullandm Bergere Buller'da burger Boulter bileenini
the wrapped component.
sarlm bileenle geiyorum.
So here I simply have to pass axios which we are importing here and which is our axios instance.
Yani burada x yln aktarmak zorundayz, burada x'im burada ithal ediyor ve x 'rneidir.
Now with that, there's one more thing we have to do. In our interceptors, we of course have to return something,
efaatilerimizde yapmamz gereken bir ey daha var. Elbette, istei gnderirken bir eyler iade etmek zorundayz.
when sending the request,
Artk bununla birlikte,
We have to return the request config so that the request can continue.
stein devam edebilmesi iin talep atmasn geri getirmek zorundayz.
and for the response, I also want to implement the response handler here where I simply returned a response,
Ve yant iin de yant ileyicisini burada uygulamak istiyorum; burada yant yalnzca bunu yapmak iin
this is the shortest possible syntax for doing that.
mmkn olan en ksa szdizimi yapar.
Now with that if we save all of that and we go back to the application and we add a burger,
imdi bununla birlikte hepsini biriktirirsek bavurudan geri dnersek bir hrsz ekleriz.
this should still work,
Bu yine de almaldr.
it does,
yle.
we can still save a burger.
Hala bir burger kaydedebiliriz.
Now let's mess something up and let's see if that also works in the burger builder container where we
imdi bireyler kartrp onun da istei gnderdiimiz Broga kurucu kapsaycsnda da
sent the request,
alp almadna bakalm.
if we now change that URL and maybe remove the .json which I said is a valid or an important
imdi unu deitirirsek, r l ve belki de dediim nokta Jason'u kaldrp, API tabannn
part of the API endpoint of forward to firebase database we're sending the request to here.
son noktas olan geerliliini veya nemli bir ksmn iletiriz, bylece yldrma isteini gnderiyoruz.
So if we remove that, it should fail.
Yani kaldrrsak baarsz olur.
So now if we try to store a burger, we indeed get a network error message here.
imdi bir burger depolamaya alrsak, aslnda burada bir a hatas mesaj alyoruz.
Now closing by clicking on the backdrop doesn't work though so
imdi tklanarak kapan ie yaramyor.
let's quickly check why this is the case.
Durumun neden byle olduunu hzl bir ekilde kontrol edelim.
Let me quickly have a look.
Bana bir gz atalm.
I'm using the wrong prop, in the modal of course, clicked is for the backdrop that prop the backdrop
Elbette yanl pervaneyi kullanyorum tabii ki tklattm motilite, zemin pervaznn motilimi ortaya kard,
exposes, the modal then uses modal closed. This is the method
daha sonra modal kapal sahtekrlk yntemini kulland zemin iin.
we tried to execute here.
Burada idam etmeye alyoruz.
So this is the property we should implement.
Yani uygulamamz gereken zellik budur.
So modal closed is the correct prop
Dolaysyla, modal kapal doru sorundur.
Now with that again if we try to send this with the wrong URL, we get the error
imdi bunu tekrar yanllkla gndermeye alrsak, hatay zeriz.
but we can dismiss it.
Ancak bunu reddedebiliriz.
So now we got global error handling in place and I'm going to fix that orders URL again,
imdi global hata ileme var ve bu sray Allegan gibi dzelteceim.
so now we're handling both the success case and the error case, we're showing a loader as long as needed
Dolaysyla, gerek avrupa'daki gerekse davann baarsn, gerektii kadar dk bir seviyede tutuyoruz.
and with that we gather robust application with a reusable higher order component which we can wrap around
Ve bununla birlikte, hatalarn ilemek iin eksenler kullanan herhangi bir bileen etrafnda sarabilmemiz iin tekrar kullanlabilir bir
any component which uses axios to handle its errors.
yksek sipari bileeni olan salam bir uygulama elde ediyoruz.